Linkage between Defect Opportunities and Probability
Welcome to this session on defect opportunities.
Recall that we had indicated there were three fundamental rules.
First, we have to have a characteristic. In this case, what we’re going to say,
is that we have a CTQ, a critical to quality characteristic.
Where that's an outcome. Y is a function of X. So, a CTQ is a variable.
It is a characteristic. You have to have that, to have a defect opportunity.
If you don't have a characteristic, you can't have a defect.
Second, you gotta have a scale of measure.
If you can't quantify the CTQ, how can you have a defect?
So, you gotta have a characteristic and you have to have a scale of measure.
Third, you have to have a standard,
a specification limit, a performance expectation.
In this case, we’re showing an upper spec. So, we have a characteristic,
a performance scale of measure, and a performance expectation or standard.
At this point we have a defect opportunity.
But right now, it's only passive, it’s potential.
It's not realizable yet, because there is no density.
There's no history. There's no performance.
It's just a scale of measure and a standard, an expectation attached.
Now, once we go out and run some parts, and operate the process,
and create some observations.
Now, we have opportunity, as we're producing parts.
Because any given part, can be above the upper spec or below the lower spec.
Remember, a defect opportunity is a set of circumstances favorable to an end.
Where the end is a defect opportunity. So, we have to have
a critical to quality characteristic, CTQ, a scale, and a standard.
Now, we can in fact have an active opportunity.
Once we start measuring the parts produced for that characteristic,
in accordance to that standard.
Those in the green is yield. Those in the red are defects.
Thus, when I know the distribution, in relationship to the standard,
I can now see the probability of a defect.
Once I have probability, I now have a true defect opportunity.
If the probability of a defect is zero,
then there is no opportunity for a defect.
Only if that probability is greater than zero, is there an opportunity.
Now, once we start making those parts, that CTQ, then we now have a probability.
So those are the things that's required to form an active defect opportunity.
A critical to quality characteristic. A scale of measure.
A performance expectation.
A process distribution, density as we call it.
Those marry together to form a defect probability.
Once I have probability, I now have the opportunity for a defect.
Now, interestingly enough, many have a hard time understanding this concept.
It's easy to try to make a simple thing complex.
So, when we talk about defect opportunities, in essence, what we’re saying is this,
listen carefully. A defect opportunity is anything that's important to us,
that we measure. So, a CTQ is critical, it’s a characteristic, it’s a quality characteristic.
It’s critical, therefore it's important we measure it and we report it.
Therefore, it's a accountable defect opportunity.
We need to account for it, as we operate our process, and accounting means reporting.
Thus, reportable defect opportunities
are those features, product, service, features,
that we feel are very important  to either us or the customer.
For any number of reasons, that we need to measure them
in relationship to the standards, to report their relative quality.
That's a defect opportunity.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.